<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solo Travel Diaries</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 01:52:36 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 01:52:36 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Singapore</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Singapore is a city of sky scrappers, I have been to this city twice and the experience just got better everytime making me fall in love with travelling alone. Singapore is a safe city, not only on paper but I could really feel that while I was roaming around places alone. If you travelling to Singapore from India, you wouldn’t find that a foreign land to any greater extent as Tamil is one of the official languages and most people speak and understand English. If you are from South of India, then definitely you ‘ll feel a lot at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travelling around&lt;/strong&gt;: The city is very well connected by public transport; MRT is very similar to the Delhi metro except that the routes/lines have names Cirle line, Downtown line, East West line, etc. unlike Delhi metro routes being called by the color Blue line, Yellow line, etc. MRT is very convenient and a heat safe mode of transport which connects the entire city well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finding an accommodation&lt;/strong&gt;: It is best that you book your stay well in advance of the travel date as the prices are higher for an immediate stay. As per my recommendation, China town is one of the most convenient places to stay and next could be Clark Quay. Don’t get lured by ‘Little India’ until you want to find yourself back in India. If you are looking out for some budget options, hostels are a better option. If you are travelling solo, booking a hostel for yourself is just the best option where you can meet other travellers, make friends and enjoy hostel activities. Make sure to read reviews before you go ahead and do any bookings, also see on the map that your hotel/hostel is how far from the nearest MRT station so that you don’t have to walk much to hop onto a MRT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things to do at the airport&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Changi Airport is one of the best airports of the world and has a lot of attractions. Grab the Changi airport map and try to cover a few things which you can on arrival and leave the rest for departure from Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in Singapore for a total of 3 days then the Singapore Tourist pass for 3 days costing SGD 30 is the best bet for you as with that you can do unlimited hop-on and hop-off on any means of public transport, else you could simply buy a EZ link card for SGD 12 and then top it up as and when required. You can go ahead and buy a sim card for yourself to avoid the hassle of finding wi-fi everywhere. Don’t think that 1GB of data is going to be enough for 7 days, my phone ate 1 GB data in 2 days while I used 4G; so simply go in for more. Now, let’s take a deep dive into what’s exciting for you at Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Places to Visit:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Singapore Flyer&lt;/strong&gt;: A ride on the Singapore Flyer is a good way to start your visit at Singapore. It gives a magnificent and panoramic view of the island city and beyond. You can see places with a beautiful top view, the best one was to be able to see the floating football ground. It moves pretty slow but going once is indeed an experience. People usually tend to compare it with London Eye which is even bigger(I haven’t been there but heard of it)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gardens By The Bay&lt;/strong&gt;: The word ‘garden’ may put you off at first but those were the most beautiful and interesting ones I might have ever been to. Gardens by the Bay is spread across 101 hectares. There is a Supertree Grove and a skyway which is way too good to take a walk on. Also, there are conservatory flower dome, conservatory cloud forest, heritage gardens and a lot more things to cover around.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Little India&lt;/strong&gt;: If you are travelling from India, then you would find it likewise else you could have a glimpse of India in Singapore. It is exactly like India with vegetable and grocery vendors across the streets, there isn’t a Indian food item you wouldn’t find there. If you are missing on Indian food in Singapore then probably that is the best place to go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Night Safari&lt;/strong&gt;: Night Safari is also one of the recommended places to visit. As the name says, the timings follow 7:30pm to 12:00 am. It is a little far off from the center of the city, so you need to plan your time accordingly in case you plan to use the public transport. Inside there are two shows of 30 minutes each scheduled at intervals and a tram ride through the jungle for 40 minutes. The tram ride was a guided tour in dark where we could spot most of the animals as per the mark. It was an incredible experience. There were walking trails as well incase somebody is interested to walk through the Jungle in pitch dark.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clark Quay&lt;/strong&gt;: That’s the place where all the clubs are! It’s quite a happening place where most people are not inside the clubs but instead sitting outside on the sil by the river and  having food/drinks. It’s a pretty lively place to be.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boat Quay&lt;/strong&gt;: Boat Quay is adjacent to Clark Quay and you find restaurants all across. The view from most of the restaurant decks is beautiful as most of them are by the river side.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sentosa Island&lt;/strong&gt;: That is one of the must visit places in Singapore. You can go to Sentosa island either by Cable car or take a mono rail to the island. The cable car is an attraction in itself though a bit costly than mono rail ticket. There are tonnes of attractions at Sentosa island and not possible to cover it all in a day. I shall share a bunch of things I did at Sentosa island.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Universal Studios&lt;/strong&gt;: Universal Studios is a theme park on Sentosa Island and is surely a must do. It has bunch of amazing roller coster rides which are themed very well like Transformers, The Mummy, Galactica and others. You need one full day to visit Universal Studios and ride all the rides. If you want to visit other attractions at Sentosa Island, keep another day aside for it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S.E.A Aquarium&lt;/strong&gt;: It is an underwater sea aquarium, interesting visit for kids or those who want to see fishes and other water creatures from a close. It’s more of a window to the ocean, pretty interesting place to go once.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marina Bay Sands&lt;/strong&gt;: That’s a hotel though but one of the most magnificient buildings of Singapore. You see three high rise pillars with a boat like structure on top which is nothing but a roof top infinity pool. The building from inside and outside is very magnificent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chinatown&lt;/strong&gt;: Chinatown is famous for the Pagoda street where you can do some shopping. Pagoda street is very well connected to the Chinatown market, in fact the Pagoda Street exit of Chinatown MRT station opens to the market itself. Also, another interesting place is the Chinatown Food street to have some local food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bugis Street&lt;/strong&gt;: Bugis Street is billed as the the largest street-shopping location in Singapore. There are modern shopping malls and restaurants around but the more lucrative part for shopaholics is the ‘street’. Depending on the dollars you have you can go on buying clothes endlessly!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orchard Road&lt;/strong&gt;: Orchard road is the retail and shopping hub of Singapore. You can find outlets of all the expensive brands along the road, a stroll under the shade of trees is worth it if you are not a fan of expensive brands!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buddha Tooth Relic Temple&lt;/strong&gt;:  This one is a temple located in Chinatown. The temple is beautiful and you ‘ll find a lot of Singaporeans there worshipping. If you happen to go, make sure you visit on all the floors covering the museum, temple where the tooth relic is kept and the roof top garden.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jurong Bird Park, Singapore Zoo, River Safari&lt;/strong&gt;: Singapore Zoo is one of the main attractions of Singapore. If you are an animal lover, you could pick up a parkhopper pass which would give you admission to both of them. River Safari includes your visit to river themed wildlife park in a boat. I did not get good feedback about the river safari and did not bother much to go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skyline Luge&lt;/strong&gt;: It is one of the attractions at Sentosa island, it is an interesting and enjoyable ride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cable Car&lt;/strong&gt;: Cable car is considered as one of the attractions and also a means to reach Sentosa island. You could reach Sentosa island in three ways, Mono rail, Sentosa Broadwalk and cable car. It’s a nice view from the cable car, but worth it only if you are there for the first time. So, the first time I went I took the cable car, returned via mono rail and the second time I preferred walking to the island which I must say was just the best walk.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wings of Time&lt;/strong&gt;: ‘Wings of Time’ is a night show at Sentosa Islands set by the sea where imagination takes flight. It’s a beautiful light show!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science Center&lt;/strong&gt;: Science centre is all about Science, mainly an attraction for kids to understand the concepts of science. It has a bunch of exhibition galleries.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FunVee Hop-On, Hop-Off bus&lt;/strong&gt;: That’s an open top double decker bus for city guided tours, you can take a ride on the bus and see all the major attractions of Singapore. You can hop on and hop off the bus as many times as you want.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;River Cruise&lt;/strong&gt;: Its a leisurely ride on the river cruise which will show you all the major attractions from the cruise, it covers Clark Quay, Boat Quay and other areas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Louis Vuitton Maison&lt;/strong&gt;: It’s a unique flagship store of Louis Vuitton which is floating :O ! The store is two floors and have all the apparels and accessories displayed neatly. Everything is super expensive there but still there were people at the checkout who intended to buy things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casino&lt;/strong&gt;: Going to casino was in my bucket list for long and I managed to do it this time. To enter the casino, you need your passport and be above 21 years of age. It is different world altogether inside! A casino for elders there looked like video games for kids in India. I did manage to play a bunch of games inside too which was an experience in itself irrespective of the fact that I lost money :D but buying chips for real dollars was worth an experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to go to any of the above places:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty simple to commute in Singapore, all you need to do is, buy a sim card, activate 3G/4G in your phone, download the app ‘City Mapper’ and let the app tell you all the possible directions from one place to another. This app has been very helpful to me during my trip as it told the MRT/SMRT routes to take followed by walking directions to reach the destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another memorable trip to my travel diary and looking for more.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/singapore/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/singapore/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is what a post on your blog looks like. This template is especially well suited for posting nice succint blurbs, much like &lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/&quot;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt; does. Of course, it will also work well with longer posts, and you can change the number of posts per page in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file. There’s no guarentee this blog will make you write as well as he does, but it will present your writings in a beautiful, clean, and distraction-free way. Try to write a little bit, every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/kerala/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/kerala/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sample post</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>/las-vegas/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/las-vegas/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
